<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research_contents on Yi Jia Liow</title>
    <link>https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research_contents on Yi Jia Liow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dietary fiber induces fat preference via the gut microbiota</title>
      <link>https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/food_pref/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/food_pref/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Eating behavior is essential to human health. However, whether future eating behavior is subjected to the conditioning of precedent dietary composition is unknown. This study aimed to investigate the effect of dietary fiber consumption on subsequent nutrient-specific food preference between palatable high-fat and high-sugar diets and explore its correlation with the gut microbiota. Specific pathogen-free mice were subjected to a dietary intervention and fed either a control or an inulin diet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food choice motives of the Japanese population</title>
      <link>https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/field_nagasaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/field_nagasaki/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Japan has undergone dietary transition and adopted Westernization in their dietary practices in the contemporary era. However, rural parts of Japan still preserve traditional foodways characterized by extensive use of fermentation products and consumption of fresh produce in contrast to increasing consumption of animal products and processed foods in the urban areas. The present study utilizes a translated Food Choice Questionnaire (FQC) tailored to the Japanese population, and qualitative data from field study to investigate the underlying motivations behind food consumption of the Japanese population residing in the rural area of Nagasaki city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of a dairy-based diet on the Mongolian gut microbiome</title>
      <link>https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/mongolian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/mongolian/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This study, conducted in collaboration with Dr. Christina Warinner and Dr. Alexander Hüebner, focuses on understanding the gut microbiome of the Mongolian population and its role in the digestion of dairy products, in particular considering adaptations to lactase persistence. In Mongolia, where dairy consumption is an important part of the diet, we are investigating how the gut microbiome composition differs between urban and rural Mongolian populations. Using tools such as MetaPhlAn and de novo genome assembly, we are exploring the metagenome-assembled genomes to delineate the mechanisms by which the gut microbiome supports the metabolism of dairy products, providing insights into the interplay between diet, genetics, and urbanization in gut health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of industrialized diet on eating behavior</title>
      <link>https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/westernization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liowyijia.github.io/research_content/westernization/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Human eating behavior is governed by the homeostatic (eating for metabolic needs) and hedonic (eating for pleasure) systems, two distinct but overlapping circuits that have evolutionary basis in motivating human appetite. Industrialization of dietary composition tilts the balance away from homeostatic towards hedonic eating, resulting in the rise of pathological eating behaviors. Research over two decades has linked diet, brain chemistry, and behavior, revealing the addictive nature of sugar and certain foods, and recent studies have highlighted the role of the microbiota-gut-brain axis in this dynamic, but the specific elements of an industrialized diet that drive pathological eating behaviors have yet to be identified.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
